<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DIY on Oliver Wilkie</title><link>https://oliverwilkie.com/categories/diy/</link><description>Recent content in DIY on Oliver Wilkie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Oliver Wilkie</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 15:10:35 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oliverwilkie.com/categories/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ornaments</title><link>https://oliverwilkie.com/2016/12/ornaments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 15:10:35 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://oliverwilkie.com/2016/12/ornaments/</guid><description>The morning of my flight home for the holidays I hastily came up with something for my family&amp;rsquo;s arts&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;crafts gift exchange.
Luckily the Techshop was pretty quiet so I could get some time on the Laser Cutter to draw up these fellas
It took three iterations to get it right, the first was too big, the second was good but needed handles. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got it though, its just a question of copy and paste to make lots!</description></item><item><title>Danish Christmas Tree</title><link>https://oliverwilkie.com/2016/12/danish-christmas-tree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 14:28:56 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://oliverwilkie.com/2016/12/danish-christmas-tree/</guid><description> Late November I made this Wooden Dowel Christmas Tree with advent-style felt ornaments (with some talented friends helping with all the ornaments).
The tree is collapsible (you just pull the branches out) which is useful for the rest of the year when its not Christmas!
Lessons learned Dowel is cheap 25 hand-stiched ornaments can take a while Once you&amp;rsquo;re half way through you have to finish! Resources and References Nalle&amp;rsquo;s House Blog Filigrantre</description></item><item><title>Walnut Tealight Holder</title><link>https://oliverwilkie.com/2016/08/tealight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 17:33:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://oliverwilkie.com/2016/08/tealight/</guid><description>Walnut Tealight Holder Still horrendous at making things with my hands but will keep trying! This is a tealight holder that is basically three bits of wood, two drill holes and glue.
Band Saw Pillar Drilling Machine 1 1/2&amp;quot; Forstner Bit Sand Paper Wood Glue Circular Saw Lessons learnt Buying Wood Walnut is a beautiful dark hardwood Walnut is expensive A DIY Store will sell wood at fixed lengths, but will cut it into pieces for you.</description></item></channel></rss>